<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Andrew&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Andrew&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 18:33:35 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SWEC Bulletin Generator</title>
      <link>/post/swec-bulletin-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 18:33:35 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/swec-bulletin-generator/</guid>
      <description>At the start of 2018 I wrote a Python script called swec-elvanto-automation.
It was a set of task runners that would manage the automatic generation of the service bulletin, as well as pretty roster emails
&amp;hellip; well, I&amp;rsquo;m officially marking it as abandonware! It worked flawlessly, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t user friendly.
And also, with my other commitments taking more time, I don&amp;rsquo;t want my involvement and role at my church to become &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;irreplaceable&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secret Agent</title>
      <link>/post/unsw-compclub2019summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 18:32:47 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/unsw-compclub2019summer/</guid>
      <description>Quick Links
What is UNSW CSE CompClub?
On writing a CTF server
 I got the opportunity to take part in my uni computer society&amp;rsquo;s highschool program (again)!
Last time (Winter 2018) I volunteered as a mentor - those people who would help guide the students.
This time around I helped out as an organiser, in particular a content writer.
That means that I get a whole day to do whatever the heck I want!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CompClub 2019 Summer CTF</title>
      <link>/post/unsw-compclub2019summer-ctf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 18:32:46 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/unsw-compclub2019summer-ctf/</guid>
      <description>Read the whole CompClub 2019 Summer Workshop post
 GitHub: featherbear/UNSW-CompClub2019Summer-CTF
Demo: featherbear.github.io/UNSW-CompClub2019Summer-CTF
During the Winter 2018 Workshop, the organiser for the security day coded up a CTF website.
 Technologies
Server: Flask (Python)
CSS: Bootstrap
Performance: RIP
 Yeah so, Flask is a great Python web framework, with all of its routing magic.
But running a server with Flask alone is not a good idea&amp;hellip;
Flask should be run in a WSGI environment, but the inbuilt Flask server is not such.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Tornado vs Flask</title>
      <link>/post/python-tornado-vs-flask/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 01:27:03 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/python-tornado-vs-flask/</guid>
      <description>Python has two great web server libraries - Flask and Tornado.
Flask vs Tornado Why Flask Flask has a much easier to use routing functionality, where you just need a Python decorator @app.get(...).
In Tornado you need to set up a site router, and all these other things (or I didn&amp;rsquo;t do it right)
Why Tornado Tornado is a non-blocking server, which is able to handle multiple requests at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whoops There Goes My AI</title>
      <link>/post/whoops-there-goes-my-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:44:41 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/whoops-there-goes-my-ai/</guid>
      <description>GitHub: featherbear/Whoops-There-Goes-My-AI
 So there&amp;rsquo;s a game on the Google Play Store and Apple App Store called Whoops! There Goes My Orange.
You play as an orange falling from the sky, and you have to avoid the red bars. Simple, right?
Yep! But rage-inducing.
Anyway, so I decided to have a crack at writing some sort of AI for this game&amp;hellip;
It&amp;rsquo;d just be a collision avoidance algorithm&amp;hellip; not really an AI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School of Codecraft and Hackery</title>
      <link>/post/unsw-compclub2018winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 18:52:17 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/unsw-compclub2018winter/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Website
Day One - Introduction to Python Day Two - Microbits Microbit by BBC is a small piece of hardware with all sorts of sensors and outputs.
The uni purchased 20 of these!
Unfortunately, the accelerometer module isn&amp;rsquo;t the best, and alot of the students couldn&amp;rsquo;t get one of the workshop instructions working.
The first activity was to build a firefly, using the wireless radios on the Microbit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>