<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Andrew&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/blog/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Andrew&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 18:33:35 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SWEC Bulletin Generator</title>
      <link>/blog/post/swec-bulletin-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 18:33:35 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post/swec-bulletin-generator/</guid>
      <description>At the start of 2018 I wrote a Python script called swec-elvanto-automation.
It was a set of task runners that would manage the automatic generation of the service bulletin, as well as pretty roster emails
&amp;hellip; well, I&amp;rsquo;m officially marking it as abandonware! It worked flawlessly, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t user friendly.
And also, with my other commitments taking more time, I don&amp;rsquo;t want my involvement and role at my church to become &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;irreplaceable&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secret Agent</title>
      <link>/blog/post/unsw-compclub2019summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 18:32:47 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post/unsw-compclub2019summer/</guid>
      <description>What is UNSW CSE CompClub?
 I got the opportunity to take part in my uni computer society&amp;rsquo;s highschool program (again)!
Last time (Winter 2018) I volunteered as a mentor - those people who would help guide the students.
This time around I helped out as an organiser, in particular a content writer.
That means that I get a whole day to do whatever the heck I want! Yeeeeet!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Tornado vs Flask</title>
      <link>/blog/post/python-tornado-vs-flask/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 01:27:03 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post/python-tornado-vs-flask/</guid>
      <description>Python has two great web server libraries - Flask and Tornado.
Flask vs Tornado Why Flask Flask has a much easier to use routing functionality, where you just need a Python decorator @app.get(...).
In Tornado you need to set up a site router, and all these other things (or I didn&amp;rsquo;t do it right)
Why Tornado Tornado is a non-blocking server, which is able to handle multiple requests at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whoops There Goes My AI</title>
      <link>/blog/post/whoops-there-goes-my-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:44:41 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post/whoops-there-goes-my-ai/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School of Codecraft and Hackery</title>
      <link>/blog/post/unsw-compclub2018winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 18:52:17 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post/unsw-compclub2018winter/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Website
Day One - Introduction to Python Day Two - Microbits Microbit by BBC is a small piece of hardware with all sorts of sensors and outputs.
The uni purchased 20 of these!
Unfortunately, the accelerometer module isn&amp;rsquo;t the best, and alot of the students couldn&amp;rsquo;t get one of the workshop instructions working.
The first activity was to build a firefly, using the wireless radios on the Microbit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>