<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Audio Visual on Andrew&#39;s Blog</title><link>/blog/categories/audio-visual/</link><description>Recent content in Audio Visual on Andrew&#39;s Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:17:54 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/categories/audio-visual/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Laptop Dock</title><link>/blog/post/laptop-dock/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:17:54 +1100</pubDate><guid>/blog/post/laptop-dock/</guid><description>November was the month of spending for me. From preparing Christmas gifts, to being too eager and impatient to wait for Black Friday / Cyber Monday sales (But do they even happen down here in Australia???).
2x Mi Band 4 smart watches
1x Shure SE215 earphones
1x Knowledge Zenith ZS10 Pro earphones
2x Logitech Spotlight wireless clickers
2x Satechi Type-C 75W Travel Charger
1x Canon EF 35mm f/2 IS USM camera lens</description></item><item><title>NewTek NDI v4</title><link>/blog/post/newtek-ndi-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 01:16:53 +1100</pubDate><guid>/blog/post/newtek-ndi-4/</guid><description>On the 13th September 2019, NDI released version 4 of their free NDI Tools software suite.
For all I care, the biggest benefits are:
KVM Support for Scan Converter &amp;amp; Studio Monitor You can use a computer running Studio Monitor to KVM into a computer running Scan Converter.
This is pretty amazing, considering how low-latency the NDI protocol is in general.
NDI Recording with Studio Monitor Originally, you had to use an NDI recorder software, but now this feature is built in natively, amazing!</description></item><item><title>RICE Rally 2019 Sydney</title><link>/blog/post/rice-rally-2019-sydney/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 23:57:22 +1000</pubDate><guid>/blog/post/rice-rally-2019-sydney/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m back at it again doing vision playback for RICE Rally 2019 at ICC Sydney!
Technologies:
Playback - ProPresenter 6 Playback - CasparCG Video Transport - NewTek NDI Video Mixing - Open Broadcaster Software See Production on a Budget
Technical:
Timecode ProPresenter 6 does not have any timecode slave triggering, and we didn&amp;rsquo;t have any software (PVP, and a Mac) on us that would allow for that.
We had to manually sync the track by counting over our intercoms&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Arduino - WiFi DMX</title><link>/blog/post/arduino-wifi-dmx/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 21:58:58 +1000</pubDate><guid>/blog/post/arduino-wifi-dmx/</guid><description>At the start of 2018, I built a cheap wireless DMX receiver as a parting &amp;lsquo;gift&amp;rsquo; to my high school (Heck, I even wrote a training manual).
Their system had i s s u e s.
Two broken lighting consoles, and the DMX cable that connects from the control room was damaged due to water damage.
So something had to be done!
img { max-height: 50vh; } I threw together an ESP8266 NodeMCU V3, a MAX485 chip, and added a barrel type DC socket</description></item><item><title>Lampwin Moving Heads</title><link>/blog/post/lampwin-moving-heads/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:33:51 +1000</pubDate><guid>/blog/post/lampwin-moving-heads/</guid><description>/**TODO - Custom theme CSS for images and tables**/ table { width: 100%; border-collapse: collapse; } td { padding: 3px; border: 1px solid #A7A7A7; } td[align=center] { text-align: center; } Download the QLC+ fixture I made (12 Channel): Lampwin-Mini-LED-Spot-30W.qxf
I recently purchased two Chinese brand moving heads from eBay
I was not expecting to receive quality, but I did receive amusement and amazement as to how much enjoyment $70 could bring me.</description></item><item><title>PreSonus StudioLive 16</title><link>/blog/post/presonus-studiolive-16/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 18:20:04 +1100</pubDate><guid>/blog/post/presonus-studiolive-16/</guid><description>My church recently bought a PreSonus StudioLive 16, and a PreSonus StudioLive 24R III as part of our Production upgrade plan.
It was a fairly straightforward process to set up everything.
A graphic equaliser with a visualiser was a big step up from the old Yamaha MG24/14FX mixer that used in the past
Issues / Feature Requests Stagebox disconnect After a long period of the SL16 being turned off, the 24R (having been on for a week) wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be detected by the SL16.</description></item><item><title>SWEC Audio Mixer Upgrade</title><link>/blog/post/swec-audio-mixer-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 18:20:04 +1100</pubDate><guid>/blog/post/swec-audio-mixer-upgrade/</guid><description>My church recently went from an analog audio console (Yamaha MG24/14FX) to a digital console, the Presonus StudioLive 16.
Why digital? A digital sound console packs a whole bunch of feature into a small(er than what an analogue system would need) form factor Software effects replace the need for purchasing hardware for each effect, which are both costly, and occupy physical space Presets and Scenes allow the mixer to recall specific layouts and settings, and to reset the channel configuration to a standard setup More inputs via a networked stagebox Remote control over USB and network Multitrack recording Simpler interface (well, less buttons and knobs) In-Ear Monitor capability The Parts Item Type Price Link PreSonus StudioLive 16 Series III Console AU$2399.</description></item><item><title>Neutrik EtherCON Kits</title><link>/blog/post/neutrik-ethercon-kits/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 23:31:12 +1100</pubDate><guid>/blog/post/neutrik-ethercon-kits/</guid><description>The PreSonus StudioLive 16 and StudioLive 24R have an EtherCON port for their AVB connection.
You could forego the EtherCON connector and just connect an Ethernet cable, but I&amp;rsquo;ve had one occassion where a network stagebox got disconnected because the cable got kicked off.
Neutrik sells several EtherCON kits, the two I bought were Neutrik NE8MC and the Neutrik NE8MC-1.
(Didn&amp;rsquo;t need the CAT6 series, which would&amp;rsquo;ve been the NE8MX6 series)</description></item><item><title>Behringer X-Touch Mini</title><link>/blog/post/behringer-xtouch-mini/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 18:20:48 +1100</pubDate><guid>/blog/post/behringer-xtouch-mini/</guid><description>Got my hands on a Behringer X-Touch Mini USB MIDI Controller (Yay for Facebook Marketplace).
Will be using this in my Lightroom editing workflow!
Configuration Changing the MIDI Mapping The X-Touch Mini has 12 white buttons. With two layers, that would give us 24 different buttons. However some of the buttons were mapped to the same MIDI control key aka - some buttons are duplicate. So firstly, we&amp;rsquo;ll need to remap the surface.</description></item><item><title>RICE Rally 2018 Sydney</title><link>/blog/post/rice-rally-2018-sydney/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 19:19:44 +1100</pubDate><guid>/blog/post/rice-rally-2018-sydney/</guid><description>In a world full of noise, how do we find what we&amp;rsquo;re really looking for?
RICE Movement is a Christian organisation that brings the message of Jesus to high schoolers (of Australia, and now New Zealand too!)
RICE Rally is their annual event, a big evangelical &amp;lsquo;rally&amp;rsquo;.
I got the opportunity to serve with my brother in the Production team (that is, lyrics and projection).
Our playground was three LED walls (and two confidence monitors)!</description></item><item><title>NewTek NDI</title><link>/blog/post/newtek-ndi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 19:19:35 +1100</pubDate><guid>/blog/post/newtek-ndi/</guid><description>NewTek NDI is a really amazing actually suite of software designed to transport audio and video data over networks.
Note: I recommend a gigabit connection between the producers and consumers, as it easily saturates 100 MB/s with all settings max&amp;rsquo;d.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it a while:
Screen recording Laptop screen streaming - Scan Converter on the laptop, Virtual Input on the desktop RICE Rally 2018 - Use OBS to create composites from several NDI sources Software Scan Converter Share your computer screen, or a region of the screen</description></item><item><title>ProPresenter 6 Stage Display Messages</title><link>/blog/post/propresenter6-stage-display-messages-client/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 23:14:04 +1100</pubDate><guid>/blog/post/propresenter6-stage-display-messages-client/</guid><description>ProPresenter 6 is great!
Except for the times when it&amp;rsquo;s not&amp;hellip; (then, it&amp;rsquo;s not great! [Wow who knew!])
PP6 allows you to send stage messages remotely from the ProPresenter 6 iOS / Android app.
Unfortunately that application is a bit clunky, and there&amp;rsquo;s no Windows / desktop app&amp;hellip;
RICE Rally 2018 was coming up, and I needed some way to send Stage Display messages via my laptop.
If only there was a HTML/JavaScript solution&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;d really come in handy&amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>