<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Andrew&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Andrew&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 15:42:27 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Firefox</title>
      <link>/post/back-to-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 15:42:27 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/back-to-firefox/</guid>
      <description>Why I left
I stopped using Firefox in the late of November 2016, when Mozilla decided to pull the plug on, and severely restricted Firefox&amp;rsquo;s add-on platform, in favour of their WebExtensions API.
This issue with this was that the WebExtensions API was relatively high-level - meaning that my favourite extensions (ie DownThemAll!) would cease to work, as they relied on low level access.
 Not being able to use DownThemAll!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Network Upgrade</title>
      <link>/post/home-network-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 21:01:21 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/home-network-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>I love GumTree, have I ever told you that? (I also thoroughly enjoy Facebook marketplace too)
Ubiquiti UniFi UAPs TEN DOLLARS EACH (No, not the ACs unfortunately.. the first ever ones.. but hey save $50 per piece)
10&amp;frasl;100 not 10/100/1000 To my dismay, these APs were only 100FDX and not 1000FDX. But my old APs weren&amp;rsquo;t gigabit either. so it&amp;rsquo;s not like my network became worse
80 8x Ubiquiti UniFi UAP 50 D-Link DGS-1210-28 40 MikroTik RouterBOARD RB1200 80 Dell PowerConnect 2848</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools of the Trade</title>
      <link>/post/tools-of-the-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 15:01:09 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tools-of-the-trade/</guid>
      <description>My Phone (Samsung S9+)  TripView Stocard Year in Pixels PhotoTime PowerAmp QMix-UC UC Surface Lightroom CC WiFiman F-Stop Contacts+ Messenger Messenger Lite BudgetBakers wallet Trello SimpleNote Squid Nine Folders Metronome by Soundbrenner Evie Authy bxActions GPS Status GPSLogger Joist Life360 Keepass2Android Mi Band Master MIFARE Classic Tool NewTek NDI OpenSimSim Google Play Rewards Sound Analyzer App Timely YouTube Vanced  My Computer My Laptop Adobe Premiere Pro CC Adobe Lightroom Classic CC Adobe Illustrator CC Adobe InDesign CC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City Hunter</title>
      <link>/post/city-hunter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 17:44:45 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/city-hunter/</guid>
      <description>Uni holidays. Preoccupied myself with watching some Korean Drama.
My friend recommended me some series called City Hunter.
And&amp;hellip; it&amp;hellip; was&amp;hellip; alright actually!
I even watched some bits at 1x speed!
 Spoiler Time
Some Koreans go and do a secret mission in North Korea.
They complete their objective, but their gov chucks a sneaky and abandons them.
One survives, then steals the newborn of a fallen comrade&amp;rsquo;s wife and raises him up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[SCAM] Masters iPhone</title>
      <link>/post/masters-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 18:41:13 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/masters-iphone/</guid>
      <description>EDIT: Well their Facebook page is down now, hurrah!
You know the saying: &amp;ldquo;If it&amp;rsquo;s too good to be true, it probably is&amp;rdquo;.
So my friend wanted to upgrade from their iPhone to a Galaxy S9+.
Personally, I don&amp;rsquo;t really care much about getting brand new goods (exceptions exist), so off to the races!
Hopped on eBay, Gumtree and Facebook Marketplace to check for some sweet deals.
I found a few classifieds from a store called Masters iPhone - supposedly located in Western Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RICE Rally 2018 Sydney</title>
      <link>/post/rice-rally-2018-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 19:19:44 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rice-rally-2018-sydney/</guid>
      <description>In a world full of noise, how do we find what we&amp;rsquo;re really looking for?
 RICE Movement is a Christian organisation that brings the message of Jesus to high schoolers (of Australia, and now New Zealand too!)
RICE Rally is their annual event, a big evangelical &amp;lsquo;rally&amp;rsquo;.
I got the opportunity to serve with my brother in the Production team (that is, lyrics and projection).
Our playground was three LED walls and two confidence monitors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>