<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Andrew&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/blog/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Andrew&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 17:44:45 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>City Hunter</title>
      <link>/blog/post/city-hunter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 17:44:45 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post/city-hunter/</guid>
      <description>Uni holidays. Preoccupied myself with watching some Korean Drama.
My friend recommended me some series called City Hunter.
And&amp;hellip; it&amp;hellip; was&amp;hellip; alright actually!
I even watched some bits at 1x speed!
 Spoiler Time
Some Koreans go and do a secret mission in North Korea.
They complete their objective, but their gov chucks a sneaky and abandons them.
One survives, then steals the newborn of a fallen comrade&amp;rsquo;s wife and raises him up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[SCAM] Masters iPhone</title>
      <link>/blog/post/masters-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 18:41:13 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post/masters-iphone/</guid>
      <description>EDIT: Well their Facebook page is down now, hurrah!
You know the saying: &amp;ldquo;If it&amp;rsquo;s too good to be true, it probably is&amp;rdquo;.
So my friend wanted to upgrade from their iPhone to a Galaxy S9+.
Personally, I don&amp;rsquo;t really care much about getting brand new goods (exceptions exist), so off to the races!
Hopped on eBay, Gumtree and Facebook Marketplace to check for some sweet deals.
I found a few classifieds from a store called Masters iPhone - supposedly located in Western Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RICE Rally 2018 Sydney</title>
      <link>/blog/post/rice-rally-2018-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 19:19:44 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post/rice-rally-2018-sydney/</guid>
      <description>In a world full of noise, how do we find what we&amp;rsquo;re really looking for?
 RICE Movement is a Christian organisation that brings the message of Jesus to high schoolers (of Australia, and now New Zealand too!)
RICE Rally is their annual event, a big evangelical &amp;lsquo;rally&amp;rsquo;.
I got the opportunity to serve with my brother in the Production team (that is, lyrics and projection).
Our playground was three LED walls and two confidence monitors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>